Hello. Good morning,
and thank you everybody for coming.
I know people are coming in, but think we're
gonna get started. The
welcome to the last day of the conference.
The today we have I'm really
excited to announce the
next speaker. Karen
Adolph is a Julia Cesar professor
of psychology and neuroscience
and professor of
applied psychology child and adolescent psychiatry
New York University She
uses observable model behaviors
to to study developmental processes,
She directs the dialogue labor
data library org and playproject.org
The and she's a fellow in pretty much
all the major society APA,
APS, triple a s,
and so on. She received number
of her rewards, including
Curt Koff kam Medal,
the CATEL Sabetical Award,
APF France Memorial Award, and
so on. It's really my
pleasure to introduce her. Welcome,
Karen.
Thank you so much for the opportunity
to talk with all of you.
So babies are the world's
best learners.
So data about how
infants acquire intelligence
behavior is useful for anyone who
wants to build intelligence
or understand intelligence.
I study behavioral learning literally
from head to toe. I study
looking behaviors, facial
gestures, manual behaviors,
interactions with objects,
pastoral behaviors, and locomotor.
Behaviors. I study infants and
children while they're alone and while they're engaged
in social interactions. In
the lab and in the home, in
controlled experiments and during
natural activity. I've
observed tens of thousands
of hours of infant behavior
in New York City, of course.
But also thousands of hours
across The US and in South
America, Europe, and Asia.
Now A word about my intellectual
Since I was an undergraduate, the ideas
of James Gibbs shaped my
thinking. His ecological
approach to behavior, his
idea that perception guides action
and that action generates
information for perception.
That behavior always entails a
wrestle between
animals and their environments
and all of that is
captured in his idea of
affordances. Eleanor
Gibson was my doctoral adviser
and I'm deeply guided by her
ideas about learning and development
and the of
function and behavior.
I want to highlight a very productive
collaboration with George Pablocos
and Peter Stone that integrates
the power of computer vision and AI
with the intelligence of infant learning.
Today, I'm gonna focus on the development
of walking. So I'm gonna tell my
story using walking as a
case study. But I think that
all of my arguments hold
for every kind of foundational behavior.
Because every behavior develops.
Walking for example,
starts out something like this.
With a baby that can barely keep
balance long enough to take few
steps. But then
a hundred days later, it
becomes something like this. A
baby who can steer and navigate
and carry things place to place.
Get where he wants to go.
Those video snippets represent
the big themes of this talk.
Behavior, it experience,
and the power of video to capture
the mechanisms of behavioral
learning and
Why focus on behavior? Because
of everything we do. It's
why we have brains and why we have
body. Why focus on
experience Because it tells you the
how and why behavior changes
with learning and development.
And why use video
Because it captures the richness
of behavior at the times scale
of human understanding.
Intelligent behavior is not
rote repetition.
Walking is more than
putting one foot in front of the other.
Intelligent behavior involves
detecting changing conditions.
Changing affordances for action.
You've got to explore to generate
perception information to guide action.
You have to form a plan. You have
to modify. Ongoing
action.
You have to find new
solutions for novel situations
Like, what is the best way
to get down this steep slope?
An intelligent behavior involves learning
to learn. That means
learning how to figure out what
to do, right now with this
body of these skills. In this
situation,
For thirty years, I've been testing
infants on crazy apparatus
like bridges and drop offs and
slopes. And gaps.
And ledges and apertures
they can walk through and apertures
they can reach through overhead
barriers and underfoot barriers,
All of it is
to understand how babies
acquire intelligence.
Behavior.
After thirty years of research,
one thing is clear. Intelligent
human behavior is not innate.
It's learned.
There's three things
that every baby must learn. They have
to learn to detect affordances, They have
to learn to explore, plan, and modify
their behaviors, and they have to be able
to find new solutions.
So one thing infants
learned to detect changing
affordances for action.
Here's an example
This is an adjustable drop off it
can have really small drop offs like
a step. That afford low commotion,
really large drop offs like a
cliff. Where locomotion is impossible.
From infants view, it looks something
like this.
Newly walking infants
do not perceive a fortitude.
So novice walkers
will repeatedly attempt to walk
down drop offs that are beyond
their abilities.
They really do. Even
on a 90 centimeter drop
off they plunge right over
the edge. Newly
walking infants behave as if they
have no clue. About the limits
of their own ability.
But with each week of walking
it leads to more and more accurate
perception of affordances. And
after several months of walking
experience, infants can now perceive
a Ford and say, they can
precisely within one centimeter
of accuracy whether a drop off
is safe. For walking.
Experience a t month old
know whether a drop off is too high for walking,
and if it's too high, they'll
find an alternative strategy.
Here's the data.
So zero here is the largest
drop off that each infant could navigate.
So the data are normalized
to each infant's ability.
The negative numbers are drop
offs that are smaller
than the threshold. So these are safe. They're
like a step. The positive
numbers are drop off are
larger than the threshold. These are risky drop
offs They're like a cliff.
And there's a really easy one centimeter
drop off and a 90
centimetre really big cliff size.
Drop off.
The blue curve represents
novice 12 old walkers.
These babies vastly over
estimate imate their own ability. They attempt
to walk over a drop off that nine
centimeters too large on 75%
of trials They attempt to walk
over the 90 centimeter drop off on
50% of trials. So
these babies had not yet learned to
perceive
Now, I've added the 18
old experienced walkers.
These guys can perceive precisely
they can and cannot do. Experienced
walkers are probability
matching. Matching the
probability of attempting to walk with
the conditional probability of
success.
And it's the same story for other
Novice walkers, do not perceive affordances
for walking stones slopes. They will
attempt to walk
down slopes that are way too steep for
their abilities. This is an impossibly
risky 50 degrees slope.
Same thing for bridges. Novice
walkers do not perceive affordances.
And this these are the same
babies doing both tasks.
But it's experienced walkers
perceive affordances on safe
and risk slopes. They can
perceive within couple
of degrees of slant
whether the slope is safe for
walking or whether it requires an
alternative strategy. Yay.
It And same thing on bridges.
They can distinguish safe from risky increments
and perceive a affordances accurately.
So an eight centimeter bridge
is currently the world record for
baby bridge walking, but this guy
is doing 16 centimeters. That's
pretty amazing.
This graph shows infants attempts
to walk on safe and
risky slopes. Novice walkers
attempt more at every increment
They attempt to walk down impossibly
steep risky slopes. But experienced
walkers perceive affordances
more accurately. Here's
the data for bridges. Novice
walkers attempt more risky bridges
than walkers.
So infants have to learn
to perceive a
With each week of
everyday experience, their judgments
become more and more accurate
What are they learning
They're learning to and to
exploit. New possibilities for action
And part of that learning
includes and
honing the right exploratory action.
The second thing that babies must
learn is how to explore.
How to plan, how to modify,
their ongoing behaviors adaptively.
On shallow slopes like this one,
experienced walking infants walk
straight down with wide, evenly spaced
steps. But
on steep slopes,
infants begin modifying their
before before they go over the brink.
And then they break
their forward momentum step by step all
the way down.
On wide bridges, infants
run straight across with long
evenly spaced steps.
But on narrow bridges, infants
modify their gait during a
and then they inched their way
across the bridge taking short
tiny slow narrow little steps.
As they make their way to
landing. Class.
Look at infants' gait modifications
on slopes and bridges.
Sure. Babies are taking shorter slower
steps on the slope and
on the bridge, But the
really important thing is that
babies have learned to modify their
gait pros not
reactively. That cluster
of footfalls right at the brink
means that infants are modifying
their gait be before they step
on the slope. Before
they step onto the bridge.
Infants have to learn to
explore, to plan, and to modify
their ongoing behavior. They learn
to change how they move just
suit changes in the local
conditions. Their
modifications are prospective
not reactive, That means they're
planning ahead of time. Not
reacting after the fact. And
the only way you can do that
is to gather it gather
perceptual information to plan
ongoing behaviors.
A third smart thing that infants
must learn is how to find
new behavioral solutions.
Infants are not learning six
association. Or static solutions.
And they search for multiple
solutions. So I'm talking about the
same baby in the same session.
For example, if it's within
their ability experienced walkers
will walk over say a 13 centimeter
drop off. But if
it's a little bit beyond their ability,
then infants will find alternatives
solutions. Like crawling over that
six teens. Centimeter drop off.
And if it's too high for crawling,
then we'll find another
solution. Like scooting down the
30 centimeter drop off in a sitting
position. Or backing down
the 30 centimeter drop off. Good.
Learning fixed solutions would
be a variable world
that needs new solutions
for new tasks.
These are data from a longitudinal
study of infants defending
slopes. The first
graph shows week of crawling.
The second graph shows weeks of
walking. You don't need to try to
parse these lines because the
the point is that the
frequency of the various strategies
change. But at every point in
development, a variety of
solutions persists.
Infants learn new
behavioral solutions to achieve their goals.
They're not learning fixed
solutions. Babies are
altering their behavioral strategies
to suit the task.
Babies must learn to search for
new solutions and to
recognize new solutions that
can work. So
what are infants learning? When they acquire
this kind of functional intelligent
behavior? I
argue that infants are
learning to learn to move.
Alright. What about precocial animals?
Those are animals that can walk
shortly after birth.
This is a photo of a baby goat peering
over the brink of Eleanor Gibson's visual
cliff. Images like
this and anecdotes
led people to believe that
precocial animals like goats
can avoid an impossibly high drop
off that they will perceive
affordances shortly after birth.
But anecdotes are not
robust experimental data so
we went out and collected robust
experimental data.
Like baby goats, and baby
horses and baby chicks
pigs are precocial. These
are 13 baby pigs
six to eight hours, after birth.
Clearly, they can walk
but can they also perceive
affordances?
We tested Piggy's at the edge of an
adjustable drop off and just
like with human babies, we lured them with
piggy snacks and toys and
sweet encouragement And as
you saw with the human babies, a
trained researcher rescued them if they
fell. On day one,
we tested 13 piglets.
13 out of 13
plunged over the edge of a meter high
drop off. So I'll show you pick
number one. Here's piggy one.
And two and three and four and five six
seven eight nine ten twelve.
Thirteen out of 13. Picks.
By day three, 11
of the thirteenth pigs were still
plunging over the meter high drop off.
I'll show you pig one.
Should be sound on.
Yeah.
And there's the other 12 picks.
Only pig number five and pig 13
showed any evidence of perceiving
affordances. So I'll show
you smart pig number
13. She actually turned her
back on the drop off and avoided
the whole sixty second trial.
Yeah. I
From day one to day three,
walking skill improved a little bit for all
the pigs. So at the best,
they could maybe walk a 25
centimeter drop off. But for
most of the pigs, perceiving
affordances did not improve from
day one to day three. The
top curves show the highest drop
off that attempted to walk
The red curve shows the smart pig
number 13 and the pink curve shows
the kind of smart
pig number five. 11
pigs show no evidence of perceiving affordance.
So we ran a second study now
with six little Kegi.
Down here. Come on. Over here.
Come on.
Repeatedly over impossibly high drop
offs. So the
study two data are the circle
symbols. We totally replicated
the findings. So
then we thought well, maybe there's something
about pigs. So in study
three, we ran 17 newborn
goats soon as they could walk.
Alright. This is the first real
experimental evidence about whether
precocial animals perceive affordances
at birth. Clearly, they do
not.
Clearly, experience is
critical. To promote intelligent behavior.
But what experience?
What's the input?
I'm gonna tell you about six
features of infants practice
regimen. Six critical things
about their experience.
I'll do them one by one. The
really important thing, number one,
is that infants are
continually learning while they're
developing.
So babies differ from robots
in a really important way.
Robots' bodies don't change. But
infant behavior develops
in a changing body changing skills
and a changing world.
Because infants bodies and skills and
environments are developing,
development constrains the
input. Baby's world is not
a blooming buzzing confusion because
development is constraining the
input. A
nice example is the transition from
crawling to walking. Because
walking literally brings more of
the world into view.
This is crawling infants view of
the world. While they're crawling,
infants heads point down
not forward. So they see mostly the
floor. In front of their hands.
But in a walking posture, the
entire room is visible.
All the things swoop into view.
Now Development expands
multimodal access to
the environment. With
George Pavlakos, our computer vision
genius, we quantified
what parts of the environment infants
see and touch and
where they go. We observed
each baby longitudinally
so repeated sessions for each baby from
two to eighteen months.
At every visit, we
tested babies in the
same fabulous playroom with
same room The playroom
was filled with interesting things to
see and objects to touch
and places to go.
At every session, we
put baby down on their backs
on that gritted mat and
same place caregivers
sat in a chair and were occupied
on their phone. And then babies had
ten minutes. To do whatever they wanted to do.
Pre rolling babies can't
even get off their back. Rolling
babies are stuck on
their belly. But
when infants can up,
they can also
to the environment So they
can explore the mat and the toys.
That are nearby. When
babies can crawl, they can get
off the mat and
space in the They can get off the mat and explore larger space in the They can get off the mat and explore larger space in the They can get off the mat and explore larger space in the playroom. Pull
up to a stand, interact with
more things.
And when babies can walk,
they go everywhere in the room. They go more.
They more. Do more.
We've rendered the room in three d
So this is a rendering not a video.
With the rendering of course you can manipulate
the room to see it from every
angle at every moment. We
can analyze every visual
manual, and
whole body contact with the
environment with centimeter precision.
We record infants from
eight camera views and use
baby mesh recovery to estimate
their body post and their three
d location in each video
frame.
Here's what pre rollers
see. While they're lying on their back
The cone shows the direction
of their gaze and when the field of
view intersects with
ceiling and a bit of the walls.
This heat map
shows the whole history
of the baby's visual exploration over
ten minutes. It's largely
limited to the ceiling above the
baby's head.
Here's the tactile
This is the input as each hand touches
the floor.
The entire history of manual access
every ten minutes It's nothing.
Here's where the baby went.
Nowhere. They hardly accessed
the room. His body.
So for pre rollers, and
rollers, they're experiences their
inputs are really limited.
Multimodal input about this fabulous
playroom is highly constrained. It's
like their world is relatively
small. So they start small.
Right?
In contrast, here's a
walking baby. So the baby can see the
ceiling, while placed on his back,
but then he has visual
access to the rest of the room as he gets
up. And moves around.
Here's a heat map of
the surfaces that one baby's eyes
touched. Over ten minutes of
activity. Infants' eyes
touch nearly every vertical surface in the
room. And it's mostly at
their eye height Their eyes only go to
the floor, they're playing with objects
on the floor and babies rarely
look at the ceiling.
Here's what the infant's hands
touched, and here I'm only showing six
surfaces like the floor or
furnishings or walls
not all the objects and
movable things. That the hands touch.
Here's the ten minute history. Of
all the fixed surface
that the infant's hands touched.
The hands are on the floor, only when
the baby's playing on the floor or going
from a sit to stand.
Here's baby's feet. So
this baby is picking up a ball and then
he's pushing a stroller around.
Right here. Alright. So
that's the trail of where his feet are going.
Here's a heat map. Of everywhere
that baby walks. In ten
minutes of spontaneous activity.
And here's the baby's path
through the room. The dark blue is
one foot, the light blue is the
other foot. Walking infants
have like unlimited multimodal
access to all the places
all this spaces all the objects.
It's unlimited
multimodal about the
world.
These data summarize where infants
go as they acquire more skills.
At first, babies barely go
anywhere, and then they cover every
inch of the room.
As infants acquire more motor skills,
they travel longer distances,
and they visit more unique areas
in the playroom.
Behavior develops
in a changing body with changing
skills and a changing world.
Bodies and skills constrain
interactions with the environment and
they filter information from
the environment.
Because infants bodies and skills develop,
that means the environment also
develops. And that means
that across development, infants
in the same environment do not
experience the same environment.
Number two,
self generated. Alright?
But then, what motivates infants to
generate all that Why do
they move?
So One common sense hypothesis
is that infants move to
get to the people and places and things that
they see. So, to study
whether where infants look
influences where they go,
we fitted them with head mounted eye trackers.
If infants really move
to go to destination, then they should
look at something while they're stationary and then
go to it. So here's what that would
look like. That baby
sees the ball and then walks
straight to the ball and gets
But it turns out those kinds
of destination directed bouts are
pretty rare.
It's also possible that babies
discover something while they're traveling.
So in a discovery doubt, infants
start out looking at whatever. They see
things like maybe that's sucks
and then they'll see something else like
the green alligator. And then that becomes
like a found goal.
Discovery bounce are also rare.
What's happening most of the time?
Well, babies are standing there looking around
and then they start moving and
there's still looking around,
and then they'll just stop
moving in the middle of the room.
Beyond arm's reach of any recognizable
person place, or thing.
Most of babies bounce don't
involve a destination at
all.
So we figured if it were really
true, that objects like toys are
not needed to instigate low commotion,
then infants should move just as
much in a totally empty room
as in a room filled with toys.
We find infants walk just
as much in an empty room as
in a toy filled room, They spend
the same amount of time in motion,
they take the same number of steps per
hour and they travel the same
distance per hour.
And infants in both conditions
go to the same low percentage
of destination. Only
thirty percent. In the toy
room, infants mostly went to toys, In
the empty room, infants went to their
caregivers and to features of the
room. Seventy
percent of the time, babies are just
running around.
What differs is that infants
in the toy room spend
less time near their caregiver
and infants in the
toy room explore more of the playroom.
Here's all of the baby's paths
ordered by the amount of area that they
cover. Infants in
the toy filled room cover
more area in the same amount
of steps.
So how can we explain
baby exploration? The
classic optimal foraging model
proposes that agents balance
for moving, like a toy,
against the cost of moving, the effort cost of
moving. So, optimal
foraging treats babies as
if they're rational explorers.
But the optimal foraging model
cannot explain baby x
exploration. Infants are not fully
rational explorers. The simulated
agents fail to move at all and the no
toy room where infants didn't
have toys to go to as a reward.
Infants don't expend energy only
to get to x external reward.
We tested the effect of
adding an internal reward
to the optimal foraging model
So here, babies are weighing the cost
of moving against probability
of an external reward plus getting
an internal reward for moving.
We called our model the
frolicking forager and it
leads the baby
exploration data.
If we remove the cost of moving,
we find that a tireless
feliker does not
baby exploration. So babies are not
just burning off surplus energy.
That's not why they move so much.
And only external reward but no
cost like a sort of tireless
forager. Cannot explain. Infinite
exploration. So babies
are not motivated solely to exploit
external rewards.
Finally, we used our models
to test the nature of the
internal reward. We
find that infants are not moving just
to burn off surplus energy,
and rewarding the model
for moving faster. And better.
Like a sort of competence motivation like babies
move so much because they wanna
practice walking and get better at walking.
Not so. That does
not am the infant data.
The frolicking forager model fits
best. Suggesting it
just feels good to move.
Movement achieves goals course, it does.
But movement is also its
own reward. At least for
babies. Infants
sometimes will move to goals goals that are
imposed by their caregiver or by
researchers or goals of their
own choosing. But infants
also move a lot
spontaneously with no goal in
sight. And no goal in
mind. All of that movement
leads to enhanced opportunities
for learning and for improvements
in their walking skill.
Here's number three.
For what infancy? What
they hear? What they say, For their
interactions with objects. And
for locomotion, crawling, walking, whatever.
Everyday consists
of immense numbers of
time distributed brief bouts
of behavior.
This graph shows the accumulated
number of steps per hour
plotted against days of walking.
Each symbol is one infant's
spontaneous walking in a lab playroom that's
set up with toys, and elevations.
Babies walk a lot. They're averaging 2,400
steps per hour. That's like
14,000 per day. Their
Fitbit would be like yes.
And we see the same thing in new samples
of infants tested in a
lab playroom set up with different toys.
And different elevations in different
configurations. We see the same thing
when we record walking in infants' homes.
And in new studies, of natural
activity in the home.
These are timelines
of walking across a two hour home visit.
Each row is a different baby.
The red bars the time they spend
walking, Blue and pink is
time they're not walking.
For each baby, walking
is time to distributed.
So their experience includes
lots of starting and stopping.
It's not continual steps like walking
on a treadmill. Alright.
Watch this baby's right right leg.
So she's standing there, and
then she takes a step and that's it. That's
the whole bout of walking.
Short bouts like that
are common across development.
More than thirty percent
of infants bounce have only one or two or
three steps. Babies
can take longer bouts than they often
do, but a lot of the time, it's
only one or two or three steps.
Number four. Maybe this
one is the most important.
Infants generate variable
Their path shape varies between straight
paths and curved paths.
Relatively few of their walking paths
are straight. Infants mostly walk
along curvy paths. And
there's curvy paths that across development.
Curved paths in brand new walkers, curved
paths and experienced
walkers. Their
step direction varies.
So their steps are omnidirectional.
They're forward, backward, and
sideways. I'm gonna play it at half
speed. So you can really see what I mean.
So watch this baby's legs.
She takes one, two sideways steps,
then one two three forward
steps, then one two. Three
backwards steps.
Less than 20% of their bouts
are only forward steps.
Most of their bouts have a mixture of
forward and not forward steps
or no forward steps at all.
And it's true across development.
They're taking omnidirectional
learning. Walking.
Taking omnidirectional steps nine months later.
That means that taking backward or
sideways steps it's not like they lost balance
and it's due to poor walking skill.
This is just how babies walk.
The context of behavior varies.
These are examples of infant walking and
small and large homes. Each color
is one hour of natural
activity Each room
poses different requirements for navigation and
steering. Each surface infants
walk on is a different exercise
and balance control and propulsion.
So natural
experience is variable. There's
variable distribution of walking bouts over time.
There's a variable length of each walking
bout. There's variable path shapes for walking.
There's variable step directions for walking. There's
variable context experience,
is variable It is
always variable.
Number five, input
is accompanied by positive
not negative. Rewards.
Infant walking is filled with
errors.
Babies fall all the time They fall
while they're playing. They trip
over their own feet. They
fall when they try to sit down.
They fall when they try to stand.
Back up. Babies fall
all the time.
On average, infants fall 40
times for each hour they're in
low commotion.
But infants are back at play
right away. Even after
a big fall this baby is
back up play. Three
seconds.
On average, infants recover
from their falls within two
seconds.
And infants don't
decrease their walking
from the objects or the places
in the room that were associated with
their falls. This baby
fell 15 times with this
stroller. But the falls don't discourage
her from walking with the stroller.
Across babies, they walk
just as much after each fall
as they had done before
each fall.
One factor that mitigates
the impact of falling
size and shape and composition of
infants body.
Infants are short and they're low to the ground
and they're like padded with baby fat.
It's like they're built to fall.
So the energy generated by infant
falls is 18 times less
than if infants were adults size.
And walked adults
speeds. The natural input
for learning is truly
immense amounts of time to
variable practice during everyday
activity. The practice
is imperfect Behavior is
filled with errors. But that's
okay. Because errors are generally trivial
and it doesn't just dissuade infants from
practice
Finally, infants natural
regimens
behavioral development.
With roboticist Peter
Stone, we simulated robots
to test whether all the
crazy variability
in infant walking is actually a good
way to learn. So this is
one of Peter's simulated
robots being trained to walk
along different paths.
And then the six of
the training is evaluated with
robot stock
soccer. Because it's kind of like real
life. It's unpredictable.
There's novel stuff going on. There's variable
stuff going on. There's other
active agents and everybody's gaggle.
In tournament one, we
asked how training robots
on geometric paths would compare
to training robots on real
baby paths.
The short answer is
babies win. Across a thousand
matches, between each pair of teams
babies show the largest average gold
In tournament two,
we used machine learning to cluster 75
infants Pav into five
groups based on the variability of
their walking. Purple
team number five was most
varied on all the measures.
Tournament two
showed that more varied
leads to better functional consequences.
It leads to more wins. And
a thousand head to head matches
of Robocop.
And another experiment we used
simulated robots to test
whether a penalty for falling is
good or bad for
learning to walk. So we tested
the impact of negative reward.
When we tested robots on
new baby walking paths,
we find that a lower penalty
leads to better skill transfer
Robots that were trained with
with zero penalty for falling
walked the farthest, on
untrained infant paths.
Simulated
robots show that variability
and a low penalty for errors
is actually beneficial learning.
Variability is a feature
of behavior It's not a bug.
Why is variability so
Because it ensures that the system
keeps practicing
It keeps getting new inputs and
new experiences. It's
pushing the system forward and development.
Low not high, penalty for
errors is better for skill acquisition
and transfer.
Why? Because a low penalty ensures
that infants or robots
maintain high motivation to keep
practicing, until they've mastered
it. So learning comes
from positive not
from negative reward.
And I want to end with a pitch
for open video sharing.
Because sharing videos going
to speed discovery above
behavior and its development. Video,
can unlock the secrets
of intelligent behavior
That's where DataBury comes in.
Databerry is the world's
only at scale digital repository
for research videos. It
provides secure ethical,
open sharing of research videos
among a community
of authorized academic researchers.
Video uniquely
demonstrates procedures and findings
This whole presentation used
video as
And video data are unique
suited for reuse.
So that new researchers can ask
new questions that the original researchers
had never even imagined. Like,
you guys could ask questions about computer vision
and machine learning and AI and
whatever it is that you do, the acquisition of
intelligence. Now
Databrae manages
and preserves videos deaf
Databury has two thousand
six seven authorized investigators
908 academic institutions
around the globe and is serving up
a hundred and twenty five thousand
hours of shared video.
To capitalize on the rich of
video, you need tools so we
created Dataview This
is, software that you can download
to your computer to human
annotate. Your video.
And of course, researchers, Kenny's
computer vision, to track
body pose and objects
and so on. So they can use videos
for machine learning and much more.
What are the benefits of video
recording, video annotation,
video sharing, and video reuse
I think it's pretty huge.
It's increased trans
and reproducibility and it
will speed up scientific progress
and improve intervention.
So that's the aim of DataBarry
you're an academic at a college
or university somewhere in this world,
you could register right now and get
authorized for act to
a hundred and twenty five thousand hours
of real research videos and it's
growing. Every week.
To sum up about how
infants acquire intelligent behavior,
In this talk, I focused
on walking but I could've
focused on reaching or sitting or vocalizing
or looking or any behavior
that any lab has studied.
Because it's all the same story
about how infants
intelligent behavior.
Here's how behavior develops.
Infants acquire intelligent
behavior from immense amounts
of time distributed variable
imperfect practice during
everyday activity with a changing
body and changing skills and
a changing world.
In short, infants are
learning to learn. That means
they're learning how to
generate the required perceptual information
from moment to moment that will
how which behaviors they can do
and how they should do them.
Finally, as a science,
we actually have the paradigms,
the tools, the technology, and the infrastructure
to really understand intelligent
behavior and its development.
We've just gotta do it.
We have time for questions. If
people can line up to the yeah.
Hello.
First of all, I think from
all the auditorium who would like to thank you
for a very refreshing
and out of the box talk And personally,
I would like to congratulate the organizer for
such a nice talk.
Questions. Question number one.
In the babies experiments, it
was very persistent appearance
of mother, and I was wondering if there is
any bias if you if we
have any about that.
Like, I I never saw a father
being the the guard
That is my first question.
Well, let me let me just answer it. It doesn't matter.
It can be Do we do we have experiments?
We have experiments? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And it it could be any caregiver, just someone
the baby. Second one, my my other question
is, in the goat,
we let it a little bit to
receive negative reward. This is how I
receive it. Because it felt
It it it fell down It
received the pain.
How much sure we are that
the negative reward is not something
don't want the babies to have pain.
But how how mature we are
that the negative reward is not also
beneficial? Because in our own life, we say that we
learn also by failure. That
are the first two questions. Yeah.
So for the apparatus
studies, we can actually analyze what
happens from trial to trial.
With human infants There's no
evidence of within session
learning. With the goats,
they do about six months of human learning
in about, a week. So
it's extremely fast. Pigs
I don't know because we had to stop testing them
after three days, But in three days, they
had learned virtually nothing.
And then in everyday activity, it's
absolutely clear that negative
reward is doing nothing.
So essentially, it's
just discounted by the infants.
Thank you very much. Yeah.
Very thank you very much for
the indeed refreshing and fascinating
presentation. My question
is about whether you've studied as well the
impact of past experiences in,
for example, exploration, So
I'm wondering whether infants
will have been explore exposed to the
breaching, crossing, or slopes,
in the past, whether they keep exploring new places.
Question is like, like,
could babies who had special experiences
on playgrounds or whatever behave
differently? The answer is no. But also,
we go to great lengths to
devise apparatuses that
no baby, at least in New York City,
has ever seen in their life. A little
bridge or gaps in the surface of support.
And so on. And actually, we
know if babies have stairs in their homes,
almost know New York City homes do have stairs.
Etcetera, etcetera. So
good question. Night
No.
You put You put the frolicking forager
model and argue that to these babies
movement is its own reward. But it looks
to me like that's a large unfamiliar
room. To them, it's huge and
there's fluff in the corner. There's all sorts of stuff. They can observe
things from different angles. How do you know
that their real reward isn't moving
somewhere to perceive the world more
and be in an unfamiliar state at which they
can understand more of things they
had never seen before. Before. Yes. That's also
a great question. So,
in a novel lab playroom, maybe
babies are just moving more,
like, the reward is just seeing more of the
room or whatever? They also
do it in the familiar environments of their home.
So I mean, I don't even know how many thousands
of babies gazillions
of steps, we've counted,
but they do it in the familiar environment of their
home, they also do it when we bring
the babies back repeatedly to the
same lab playroom set up exactly
the same way. So
it's really important to distinguish
a functional consequence for
learning and development from a motivation
to do it. Like, you are a
smart adult and you might, like,
upgrade your computer even though
it's gonna be a pain in your butt in the beginning
because you know it's gonna pay off down the
road. Right? But a little
baby human, puppy, goat,
pig, whatever, how
do they know that, you know, they should move
around a lot right now because gonna
be giving them all these valuable
experiences. And if it's an animal, it's gonna help
them to wrap and tumble play
and have sex and, you know, initiate
dominance and blah blah blah. They
don't. They're a baby. They
just need to do it. So you have to separate
the functional consequences development
and learning from the motivation for doing it.
All those things are true. There's
really good functional consequences
moving around. But
if you have to build that into the
baby that they know about the end point when they're
still a baby, That's a cheat.
Thank you.
Yeah. Hello. Thank
you for the, wonderful talk.
And very thought provoking talk as well. So,
have a bit of an out of distribution question, I
guess. So
have LLM agents now, and they
do tasks for us. Right? But we see in
them this problem of overconfidence. I
think in many I've
heard about it. During many in
many times during this conference. I can't I can't
hear you at all. I don't No?
No. Can you guys hear him?
I can't hear it up here. Oh.
Try it again and just talk really slow. Okay.
Yeah. So just say it
again. So I was talking I was saying
that we have LLM agents now.
And they do tasks for us, but we see
in them this problem of overconfidence.
Which is I would say that they don't
properly account for the context in which they
are taking actions. And there are
even companies like Turing for
instance, which try to
solve this problem for their clients by
training, essentially.
So it's a bit of a high level question.
But, do you think that this sort of
overconfidence can be seen as a
lack of ability to see
affordances. And
maybe a immediate follow-up is that
you know, walking is very different from business.
So can we apply insights
from your area of study to developing
agents which can see affordances?
I think I think yes. And
I heard about 80% of that, and I'd
love your question if if I understood
it. So I think
the question is, like, these babies appear
to be overconfident. Like they're trying
things that are far beyond their ability.
You know, they could also have not perceived
affordances by being
super under confident, you know, like, I don't
know if I can I'm not gonna try
anything. Right?
So one interesting thing is that infants
of of all the species I know
about, are
always overconfident. Like, they just
try things, so they'll false alarm rather than miss.
Like, their errors are always in that direction,
but Whereas, like elderly
people, for example, are exactly the opposite
maybe I can do it, but I'm not gonna try it.
And we've tested elderly people. So it's
that's actually true. Mhmm.
So I think if you have a system
that it can mistakes,
so like a human baby,
it's got caregivers. You
know, if a goat is
has to navigate a mountain
Craig thing whatever
too early in its development, it's gonna
die. But there's other goats. You know?
So it's it's like the whole
system if it
can be built to allow for failure, so
like this overconfidence
where you just try things
and then winnow it down rather than like
I don't know. You know, like at first
babies fall, because they're just standing
there and they lift their arm or
their head. Like, you don't want the
baby to learn from negative reward like
okay. I'm just gonna stand here
and not turn my head or lift my arm.
You want them to do stuff but
they have to be robust to errors.
Mhmm. So I think it would be I mean,
I think these kind of questions and, you know,
testing it in
AI systems is amazing and would be
really fruitful for both sides. Mhmm. Yeah.
Yeah. If I may, I think also
seems to be difficult is how do we generalize
the idea of affordance from walking
to doing actions in business?
Doing actions in Like, doing actions in
business, extracting data from documents. Right?
I don't know.
Like That's fair. Like moving from, like,
like, act physical actions to sort of
cognitive actions
Yes. And Actions which have been actions in business?
I have no idea. Much delayed reward. Right?
But this is more of a very long term pay grade. I
have no idea. Thank you.
Nothing.
Hi. Thank you for the amazing
talk. And so my question
is if infants
don't exhibit follow version and they also
have not been exposed to apparatuses like
the CLIF fall or the bridge.
If, like, prior in their life, then
what do you think contributes to their ability
to navigate these
obstacles? I really do think
it's something like learning to learn. So
it's not even really your risk It's
just like, you learn for whatever
action system you have
what kinds of information generating
behaviors you can do and which
ones are useful. And then in the
moment, you figure it out. Like,
I got on new shoes and, like, what can
I do? Are they sticky or slippery?
And in the moment, that's what people do.
You're figuring out right now what
can I do? So the
learning is how to figure it out.
It's not knowing any answers.
So they just need enough every
day experiences tons
of it, brief bouts, time to distribute
them, really really varied. It doesn't really
matter what the particular experience is. Are.
Thank you. Yeah.
Let's do one more question.
Thank you. So first
of all, it's very interesting research you guys
are doing. I'm glad to be
participating in this presentation, but
one small question I have is did you
guys do any testing with small turtles
that live on lakes and so on? Because
they are also precautionary. Right? They start walking,
walking very early.
Even if not, I have as much anecdotal I've
had since, I was a small
kid, a pet turtle. And she had
that behavior of we if
if we left it her on a table or a sofa,
she would immediately walk out and not
be have any care related to the size
of the fall. It was a step, if she
could, go in, she was just fall
on the ground sometimes on her back, and we had to help
her. And nowadays,
she do see she is careful about going
on ledges and looking before and maybe
taking a decision. Sometimes she will still go, but
she would be careful about it. And
she still has the behavior that you
mentioned about the bouts walking towards the
goal. And mainly the goal for her
is eating. She she goes crazy
when we, show her a biscuit of the
the food we give to her. And
if she sees it, or even the
just the container of the food, she
will tunnel it as in ignore all
obstacles and and environment
and just walk straight to it. Like,
she won't consider the even the path
to it. She will just go straight to it.
So, did you guys do
or see in the literature any test, using,
reptiles or turtles in general?
Because Okay. The turtle thing,
I love that. I was
in Jamaica once and I got to see the
sea turtles hatch and then crawl out of
their hole and go to the ocean,
and I was very
interested in it and read about it and wrote a little
bit about it.
I'm not sure about Affordant's perception
in a turtle, like, in the sense that I was
talking about.
What is clear is they have different
patterns of coordination. So when they're
on dry land, they move their limbs
differently than when they're the
water. And can imagine me with my cell
phone, you know, like, bumping with
the babies and video video recording
it all.
So But all the animals that
anyone has ever studied,
the the that that can move, like, from
a chicken and egg to, you
know, a baby human or whatever. They
move their limbs in utero or in the
egg. They move their limbs as an embryo
or as a fetus. And so they have
lots of patterns of coordination available to them.
How it is that, you know, a baby
turtle can immediately,
you know, switch I forget what they do,
you know, this and then they switch to this or whatever.
I don't know, kind of amazing.
It also turns out that human infants
in the 19, Myrtle McGraw did
these studies. She took newborn babies
and dropped
them in, a
swimming pool. Up at Columbia University,
and they will also move
move their limbs.
It's it's really, really interesting sort
of the physiology like, you know,
I mean, it's true. Goats and pigs can
stand. Newborn
human infant or newborn puppy or cat or
whatever don't have the physiology to stand.
Like they their limbs cannot hold their body
weight. There's like the physiology
of it, There's the movements and
the practice of moving, you know, even
pre birth, And
then there's perceiving affordances
which is really like the intelligent part of
behavior where you're taking like
the is what I can do and this is what
I can get perceptually about the
world and mapping them to each other.
A smart relation. I
don't know for the turtles about that,
So but
Yeah. As a curiosity, like, they seem
to share this type of transition of
not having those affordances, just
going off the ledge and then slowly she
learned. I just noticed this,
similarity to your experiments.
There there are a few published papers about
turtles. Perceiving affordances.
Actually. Okay.
Thank let's thank the speakers. It was fascinating
talk. And you're gonna be around
to answer more questions. Right?
Karen? You're gonna be
around to answer more questions. People have?
Yeah. Yeah. Sure. Of course.